# TRISTAN NELSON

307 Sugar Tree Lane, South Burlington VT | tnelson380 @gmail.com | 804.944.3156 linkedin.com/in/tristan-nelson-63b4a1b2/

## **FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER**

I have 10+ years' of diverse experience in project-based work and have discovered a genuine passion for software development – tracing the nuances of complex problems or collaborating within a team to solve them. In academia my curiosity drove me to develop crucial soft skills such as critical thinking and analysis to pursue meaningful historical research. Outside of academia, this mindset has led me from starting a farm-to-table pop-up, to serving as an AmeriCorps VISTA, to helping community stakeholders negatively affected by the creation of the Shenandoah National Park. The common thread found in all my roles is collaboration; I love being part of dynamic teams working towards a shared goal.

- Collaboration, Communication & Community
- Critical Thinking, Research, Analysis & Writing

- Data Structures / Library Science
- Project & People Management

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS SUMMARY**

Languages	CSS   JavaScript   HTML   Apex/Java (exposure)
Frameworks & Libraries	
Server-Side Coding	ExpressJS
Version Control	Git   GitHub
Databases	MongoDB   MySQL (learning)   AWS (learning)
CRM	Salesforce
Testing	Cypress   Mocha
Product Management	Agile Development   QA   Product Lifecycle
Other Skills	

# **EXPERIENCE**

AdMagic Burlington, VT Mar 2021 – Apr 2021

Specializes in the creation, fulfillment, and manufacturing of custom playing cards, card games, board games, and video games. Fullstack Developer – Capstone Project, Burlington Code Academy

Member of a 3-person team (hybrid consultants/interns) tasked with creating from scratch an Executive Sales Dashboard to solve a big data challenge for a company which lacked a centralized sales data repository; the dashboard was constructed to be incorporated into the current Executive Information Platform within Salesforce. The application will also provide sales reporting solutions to company's clients. To show sales analysis, the dashboard hosts a variety of filter tools which are responsive to real-time database updates and user input.

- MongoDB and Atlas Cluster were used to anchor the prototype and is scalable to handle company's full data stream
- Created interactive choropleth map to convey national and global sales numbers
- Used Apex Charts to develop a variety of statistical measure and data displays
- Developed advanced functions to query the database based on user input
- Front-end styling from scratch/hand-rolled

Front-End: React | React ApexCharts | React Leaflet | JavaScript | Bootstrap | CSS

Back-End: NodeJS | ExpressJS | MongoDB

Transitional Roles	Virginia	Apr 2018 – Apr 2021
Michael J. Woldow & Company, Richmond, VA	Sales Representative	Mar 2020 – Apr 2021
Able Solutions, Harrisonburg, VA	Production Associate	Apr 2019 – Mar 2020
27 Lions, Marion, VA	Kitchen Manager	Apr 2018 – Oct 2018

James Madison University Harrisonburg, VA Aug 2016 – May 2018

Public research university.

Executive Editor – Madison Historical Review ...... Aug 2017 – May 2018 Teaching Assistant ...... Aug 2016 – May 2017

As <u>Executive Editor</u>, managed editorial board, developed content strategy, and coordinated publication scheduling. Reviewed and published original work by Master's level students in a variety of historical fields. As a <u>Teaching Assistant</u>, led two discussion sections for 225 US History, graded assignments, and assisted professor in managing the class.

## Exploring Rockingham's Past - Project

Harrisonburg, VA

Feb 2017 - Apr 2018

Multi-year public history project supported by James Mason University (omeka.lib.jmu.edu/erp/).

Project Founder (for James Madison University) ......Feb 2017 – Apr 2018 Intern (for Rockingham County Circuit Courthouse) ...... May 2017 – Aug 2017

As a <u>Project Founder</u>, built a digital collection from courthouse records, offered interpretations, employed JMU history graduate students, engaged with the community, and furthered historical knowledge. As an <u>Intern</u>, developed a comprehensive digital archiving strategy that emphasized collaboration, transparency, and inclusiveness.

Digitized 6,207 Skyline Drive legal records and processed them through Adobe OCR

### **EXPERIENCE** (CONTINUED)

- Developed an online platform to host the project and all digital collections using Omeka
- Built collaborative network between Rockingham County Circuit Courthouse, JMU History Department, JMU Libraries and Educational Technologies, and the regional community

Emory & Henry College Emory, VA Jan 2014 – Aug 2016

# **Archive Project Coordinator**

Comprehensive 3+ year, outcome-based historical archiving project in collaboration with the Wilderness Road Regional Museum in Newbern, VA. Deliverables included: Master Registry of Documents and Records, Master Index of Names, Master Registry of Photographs, Comprehensive Finding Aids, Secure Archival Storage, Digital Storage with Recommendations for Best Practices, Training Video for museum staff/volunteers, and a Final Report.

- Project-by-the-Numbers: 97 students, 10,000 student hours, 15,000 summaries, 30,000 names indexed, and 100,000 documents archived
- Developed a coded database/accessioning system for the construction of a multi-faceted archive
- Trained students how to process historical documents, such as reading difficult script, analyzing historical context, interpretation, and coding

## AmeriCorps VISTA at Habitat for Humanity

Glade Spring, VA

Jun 2012 - Jun 2013

Americorps VISTA is a national service program designed to alleviate poverty.

AmeriCorps VISTA ......Jun 2012 – Jun 2013

ReStore Manager, Habitat for Humanity ......Jun 2012 – Jun 2013

Managed ReStore as an AmeriCorps VISTA, assisted customers, and helped with store bookkeeping.

• Developed a volunteer management program that included basic core documents, recruitment strategy, new volunteer orientations, recording volunteer hours, setting store policy, and scheduling

# **INTERNSHIPS**

#### The Birthplace of Country Music Museum

Bristol, TN

Jan 2016 - Aug 2016

Intern - Digital Media & Special Collections

Audited inventory, developed artifact location system, and helped set up exhibition: Made in Tennessee: Manufacturing Milestones.

Blaine Law, PLLC Plymouth, NH Aug 2011 – May 2012

Intern

Assisted with clerical duties, reviewed legal documents for accuracy, and developed a detailed database for digitizing old case files.

# **EDUCATION, CERTIFICATIONS & COURSEWORK**

• magna cum laude; Deans & Presidents List; Student Showcase of Excellence in Research; Outstanding History Major Award

# Certifications & Coursework

Certifications & Coursework		
Full Stack Software Developer Certificate (720+ hours) Burlington Code Academy		(expected) Apr 2021
JavaScript After Hours Course (160 hours)	Burlington Code Academy	Nov 2020
Masters Coursework (27 credits)	James Madison University	Aug 2016 – Apr 2018
Audited two GIS Classes (144 hours)	Emory and Henry College	May 2016

	COMMUNITY	
Youth, High School, and College SoccerFarm Food (farm-to-table pop-up)	Trail Maintenance VolunteerRefereeOwnerVolunteer in Service	2013 – 2018 2013 – 2015
	CONFERENCE PRESENTATIONS	
·	Examine the Relationships Between Slaves, Poor Whites lison University; Phi Alpha Theta Biennial Convention	
	Analysis of Claytor Lake; James Madison University;	2017